<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughts on notes.tiago.dev</title>
    <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/categories/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thoughts on notes.tiago.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©2021 notes.tiago.dev.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://notes.tiago.dev/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/thoughts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/thoughts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-am-i-starting-a-blog&#34;&gt;Why am I starting a blog?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am creating this blog as a sort of a personal growth record keeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The posts I am creating are usually around the areas of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;books I am reading or listening to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my endless quest of working on projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a public &amp;ldquo;fuck yeah list&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I read and listen to book, I take notes.
Doing that really helps to critically understand what I am reading and it helps to retain knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short words, this method goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write what you think you are going to be reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read a chapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write about what you have just read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;before you start reading the book again, read through your notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some videos on the method I described:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z-GtGH57J9I&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Big Think : How to remember everything you read | Shane Parrish&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9fvUYmJcqWg&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Big Think : Want to get more from books? Stop reading them cover to cover. | Shane Parrish&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been tracking all the projects that I have been working on.
There are over 20 of them. None are never trully done.&lt;br&gt;
There is always something else to thinker with. Something else to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are my creative outlet. It is probably one of the things I enjoy doing the most in life.
Some of them are pretty cool and worth sharing, I think :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fuck-yeah-list&#34;&gt;Fuck Yeah List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is right. A &amp;ldquo;Fuck Yeah List&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br&gt;
I learned this &amp;ldquo;concept&amp;rdquo; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.docjamesw.com/&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Doc James Whittaker&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
It is simple a list of accomplishments that I am proud of.&lt;br&gt;
Whenever I need a pick me up, I can come here and read &amp;ldquo;my fuck yeah list&amp;rdquo; and feel better about myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is my motto? this up here ^ </title>
      <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/motto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.tiago.dev/motto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was taking a class in called &amp;ldquo;How To Make Great Decisions&amp;rdquo; at the Seattle community college (thanks Microsoft for sponsoring it!),&lt;br&gt;
I had to keep a daily journal. One of the questions I had to answer in one of these days was &amp;ldquo;What is your motto?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I thought about it, my mind went straight into a message that I used to have on my way out of my room.&lt;br&gt;
That message was &amp;ldquo;The Staying Speed&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was something I came up with a long time ago when I used to practice kung fu. I read a lot about Jeet Kune Do and other quotes and teachings from Bruce Lee. I think I got that idea from those, but I could never find it mentioned anywhere. So if you have heard of this again, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To me, the meaning behind &amp;ldquo;The Staying Speed&amp;rdquo; is&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;hellip;about finding the right amount of time and effort needed to reach a goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put too little effort and time (how often you do something) and you won&amp;rsquo;t accomplish it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put too much effort and time and you might get burned out, bored, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Staying Speed&amp;rdquo; is&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
the right balance of the amount of effort and time you put into a goal.&lt;br&gt;
The speed is not always the same. It depends not only on what you are working on, but also your emotional state as well.
Knowing that, allows you to recognize when it is too little and when it is too much and adjust so you can accomplish your goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>