<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>powershell on notes.tiago.dev</title>
    <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/tags/powershell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in powershell on notes.tiago.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©2021 notes.tiago.dev.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://notes.tiago.dev/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First Week @ HomeTeam GameDev</title>
      <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/thoughts/hometeam-gamedev-first-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/thoughts/hometeam-gamedev-first-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-did-i-stumble-onto-hometeam-gamedev&#34;&gt;How did I stumble onto HomeTeam GameDev?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been looking for a place where I could collaborate with others on a game.&lt;br&gt;
This is something I already do with some friends. However, I wanted to do it in a more global scale.&lt;br&gt;
I started looking into open source games and I did find quite a few, but the games themselves were already pretty well stabilished and I didn&amp;rsquo;t see much about what I could do on them.&lt;br&gt;
Fast forward a couple of weeks, I am in a training and someone drops the name &amp;ldquo;HomeTeam GameDev&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br&gt;
I take a look and I get very skeptical. &amp;ldquo;Wait&amp;hellip; what? a paid &amp;lsquo;membership&amp;rsquo; to join a group where all the games made are free and everyone owns everything they make? and all assets are made within the group itself?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
That just sounded weird to me, but I decided to reach out and see if I liked it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-week&#34;&gt;First Week&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-experience&#34;&gt;Initial Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I joined the group, I was amazed by the amount of content and organization of the group.&lt;br&gt;
I dove right into that info and started watching the weekly videos of the project and I really liked what I saw.&lt;br&gt;
I cloned the repo for two games (Ionic Defender and Duck Slayer) and I started adding things.&lt;br&gt;
It was really weird at first to just make changes by following a task board without asking anyone for more info on it.&lt;br&gt;
I went to sleep and next morning, someone had built upon that.&lt;br&gt;
Day after day the same thing happened.&lt;br&gt;
Within that week, I saw Ionic Defender go from what to me looked like a prototype into a ready to be released game. &lt;br&gt;
It was trully amazing to see that happen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-mentors&#34;&gt;The Mentors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the many years of content that got created by this group on how to work well within this culture, there are also mentors in the group.&lt;br&gt;
They reached out to me give me tips here and there to communicate better (i.e. use each tool for their specific purpose), read here about more details on how to pitch a game, go there to see the bio of the people in the group.&lt;br&gt;
This was a great set of guidance that really helped me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-connections&#34;&gt;The Connections&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can already tell that the people in this group are very friendly and I feel like are interests align really well.&lt;br&gt;
I know that the connections I am building here will be very interesting.&lt;br&gt;
The group creator (Chris DeLeon) also posted about a panel hosted by IGDA LA that was word for word answering a question I had (more on that later).&lt;br&gt;
I went to the panel and heard many inspiring and motivating stories. People in the audience asked question that I had and did not know I had.&lt;br&gt;
The answers were very personal and honest. I loved it. I took so many notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something special here at HomeTeam GameDev.&lt;br&gt;
I have seen similar structures at &amp;ldquo;Maker Spaces&amp;rdquo;, but this is different somehow.
I am really looking forward to understanding why I think that there is something special about this structure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Panel @ Geeking Out Kids of Color</title>
      <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/thoughts/gokic-career-panel-2021-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/thoughts/gokic-career-panel-2021-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I volunteered for one hour to speak at a career panel.&lt;br&gt;
The panel was organized by GOKiC (Geeking Out Kids of Color) and Collective Youth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I helped start GOKiC as a board member.&lt;br&gt;
Recently, I stepped out as a board member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was really great to see the work of the non profit from the point of view of a volunteer.&lt;br&gt;
It made me really proud to see how organized and big the organization has grown. ❤&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some awesome people at GOKiC making a real impact on people&amp;rsquo;s lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;career-panel-ask&#34;&gt;Career Panel Ask&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GOKiC approached me about the career panel via email.&lt;br&gt;
I signed up through their website.&lt;br&gt;
Soon after I was contact with some guidelines on what we could speak about during the career panel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review where you’re from and how you got to where you are now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did you overcome challenges in education and work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is it like working in your role?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s one piece of advice you would give to a college student?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and then a QA session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-did-i-present&#34;&gt;What did I present?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is, let me know if any of it was helpful to you: &lt;a href=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/misc/tiago-gokic-career-panel-2021-04.pdf&#34;&gt;career panel presentation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If you have any questions, send me a message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;qa-session&#34;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A Session&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly the students were very quiet&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;hellip; except for one student who typed in the chat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I want to be a Software Engineer at Microsoft&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked her about it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there something we can help you with?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She mentioned how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She heard about software engineering as a really cool thing and how Microsoft was really awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She also said she was learning programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, the panel, encouraged her and told her that she was doing the right thing (learning to code) to become a software engineer.&lt;br&gt;
After the panel was done talking, I really wanted to know how I could help, so I asked her what year of college she was in or what year in high school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She came off mute&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;hellip;and said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am in middle school&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;think about it carefully&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
That student in middle school was attending a panel for college kids about careers and she was seeking advice on how to become a software engineer at Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait. What? Did I hear that right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;yep. I did and it made my week. ❤&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really don&amp;rsquo;t know how to end this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except by saying how amazed I am by the drive of that middle school student and how GOKiC has enabled her to connect with people who perhaps were able to give advice that may help her achieve her goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The gito alias</title>
      <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/hacks/gito-alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/hacks/gito-alias/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/misc/gito.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;gito matrix&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often need to open a repo&amp;rsquo;s webpage to look at PRs, get code reference to others and many other reasons.&lt;br&gt;
So I created an alias that makes navigating from my terminal to the repo&amp;rsquo;s webpage super easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A coworker actually showed me part of this.&lt;br&gt;
He had an alias that echoed the repo&amp;rsquo;s url.&lt;br&gt;
So I thought, &amp;ldquo;oh, I can make a command that opens a browser window with that output!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the git command to get the url is pretty simple: &lt;code&gt;git config --get remote.origin.url&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After that, do some regex magic and open a browser with the url! 😄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bash: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiagosomda/28be45e7b22e72a70996f6ba2b218a39&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/tiagosomda/28be45e7b22e72a70996f6ba2b218a39&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;powershell: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiagosomda/f6c97a9ffbfb686048895cca2c099b58&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/tiagosomda/f6c97a9ffbfb686048895cca2c099b58&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you improve it or if you have any other useful commands, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mental Load : What do Women think about?</title>
      <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/books/the-mental-load/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/books/the-mental-load/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/books/the-mental-load.png&#34; alt=&#34;book cover for the Mental Load&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently read &amp;lsquo;The Mental Load: A Feminist Comic&amp;rsquo; By Emma and I learned a lot! As I read each chapter, I took notes and today I reflected on them. I highly recommend this book to the women and men of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-this-book-about&#34;&gt;What is this book about?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/39196352-the-mental-load#:~:text=The%20mental%20load%20is%20an%20intersectional%20feminist%20comic,the%20main%20focus%20here%20is%20on%20the%20domestic.&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;review by Nancy O&amp;rsquo;Toole explains it well&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mental load is an intersectional feminist comic that uses simple illustrations to convey current issues. While the content goes beyond this, the main focus here is on the domestic. We already know about the imbalance in hours spent on activities such as cooking, cleaning, and child care, and how that negatively impacts women (especially those who work full time), but what about the impact of the mental load? The strain that comes from mentally balancing the dozens of seemingly small tasks in the household that men are, too often, blind to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-did-i-read-this-book&#34;&gt;Why did I read this book?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the review says above says &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;small tasks in the household that men are, too often, blind to&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; I wanted to know more about what those things were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, let me tell you about 3 things that prompted me to read this book once I saw it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;first--my-mom&#34;&gt;First : My Mom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I got married, my mom would tell/ask me if I was doing my part in the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip; and honestly, I thought I was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;second--deciding-to-be-equal-partners&#34;&gt;Second : Deciding to be Equal Partners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I listened to the audio book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.audible.com/pd/The-Moment-of-Lift-Audiobook/1250317045&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;The Moment of Lift - by Melinda Gates&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
In it, Melinda talks about how she and Bill strive to be equals in their marriage and also in their foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I thought this was a great idea!&lt;br&gt;
We do not want one of us &amp;ldquo;wearing the pants&amp;rdquo; in our relationship.&lt;br&gt;
We want to be equal partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;third--understanding-that-which-i-did-not-even-know&#34;&gt;Third : Understanding that which I did not even know&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I take around 30 minutes every Sunday to have a marriage meeting.&lt;br&gt;
The meeting name sounds very formal, but this is actually a very intimate moment of our lives where we reflect on the week that has passed.&lt;br&gt;
It is composed of four sections where we get to appreciate each other, discuss chores, plan for good times, and talk about our problems and challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things we talked about was how to become more equal and hence how to split up chores more evenly.&lt;br&gt;
There were some easy things that we could split, but there were also a couple of things that she did without really thinking about, but it nonetheless added to her &lt;strong&gt;Mental Load&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
As we worked through these, I realized that she did so many things around the house that I was not even aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found out about marriage meetings via a podcast that my friend showed to me.&lt;br&gt;
Here is the episode: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/articles/podcast-611-how-a-weekly-marriage-meeting-can-strengthen-your-relationship/&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Art of Manliness - Podcast #611: How a Weekly Marriage Meeting Can Strengthen Your Relationship&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a book about it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Reclaiming-Conversation-Power-Talk-Digital/dp/1608682234&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Marriage Meeting for Lasting Love by Marcia Naomi Berger&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;answering-why-did-i-want-to-read-this-book&#34;&gt;Answering: Why did I want to read this book?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be the best husband that I can be.&lt;br&gt;
I want to be the best men that I can be.&lt;br&gt;
I want to be a better ally to women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is too much inequality between men and women around so many parts of our society.&lt;br&gt;
It is up to each and every one of us to learn and try to be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-what-did-i-learn-from-the-book&#34;&gt;So what did I learn from the book?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should read it and make your own conclusions.&lt;br&gt;
The book is packed with very deep and important issues and yet it is very short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested, here are the top five things that I want to highlight:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1--you-should-have-asked&#34;&gt;1 : &amp;ldquo;You Should Have Asked&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often in a relationship, we may think that we are doing more than our partners.&lt;br&gt;
That is when little fights start, one might say &amp;ldquo;why didn&amp;rsquo;t you put the dishes in the dishwasher?&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; the other responds, &amp;ldquo;you should have asked&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
and etc&amp;hellip; the book goes into more examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, try and understand what each of you does in the house. 
Ask everyone to keep a list where they add the things they are doing around the house.&lt;br&gt;
and then, once a week, review that list and start to divide them up more equally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2--oh-wow-she-is-angry-calm-down-and-did-you-see-how-these-vandals-destroyed-the-city&#34;&gt;2 : &amp;ldquo;Oh wow, she is angry. Calm down&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Did you see how these vandals destroyed the city?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second chapter of the book is called &amp;ldquo;Violence of the oppressed&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br&gt;
It is about how fingers are usually pointed to the people being oppressed and not the oppressors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, there was A LOT of news coverage on the destruction around BlackLivesMatter protests.&lt;br&gt;
And yet, there was little talk about the inequality that black people in this country (and around the world) suffer. 
There was no coverage on how black people have this gigantic mental load about what they need to do to avoid being victims of police brutality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dress well, drive nice cards, act calmly, speak well&amp;hellip; the list goes on and on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is women at work (in tech, but I am sure in other places too), they cannot act angry or express their opinions in a stern way.&lt;br&gt;
Some men in those environments see those behaviors as unfit for women, when on the other hand it is completely okay for men to act like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3--episiotomy&#34;&gt;3 : Episiotomy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a practice done during childbirth that is brutal and not necessary, in most cases.  Read more about it here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parents.com/pregnancy/giving-birth/vaginal/qa-do-i-have-to-have-an-episiotomy&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.parents.com/pregnancy/giving-birth/vaginal/qa-do-i-have-to-have-an-episiotomy&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4--hijabs&#34;&gt;4 : Hijabs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 4 in the book, &amp;ldquo;Show me that Bossom&amp;rdquo;, caught me by surprise.&lt;br&gt;
It uses a clever story that changed my views on hijab.&lt;br&gt;
I always viewed hijabs as a tool of men to oppress and control women. &lt;br&gt;
So, of course, I never liked it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, now, I think differently. Here is what I think about hijabs:
If a woman wants to wear a hijab. It is their right to do so.&lt;br&gt;
I won&amp;rsquo;t force them to wear or not to wear them.&lt;br&gt;
It is their body and their belief.&lt;br&gt;
They are in control of how and how much they want to show their bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5--how-was-the-holiday&#34;&gt;5 : &amp;ldquo;How was the Holiday?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A woman takes her paid leave to take care of her newborn.&lt;br&gt;
She is welcomed back with &amp;ldquo;How was the Holiday?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
Next time I hear someone saying &amp;ldquo;holidays&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;maternity leave&amp;rdquo; I am going to call them out.&lt;br&gt;
Taking care of a newborn is not a holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women who have just given birth go through so much.&lt;br&gt;
Their body needs to heal AND they are taking care of their baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got a puppy last year and woooooooow, I hear a newborn baby is soooo much more work than puppies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have since then a deeper appreciation for my parents and mad respect to single parents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go read this book.
If you have men and women that you care about in your life, show them this book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspective Wand : Experiencing Superluminal in VR</title>
      <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/projects/perspective-wand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/projects/perspective-wand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/projects/perspective-wand-000.gif&#34; alt=&#34;perspective wand example&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;have-you-heard-of-superluminal&#34;&gt;Have you heard of Superluminal?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If not, check it out!&lt;br&gt;
I really enjoyed playing it : &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1049410/Superliminal/&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;link to Superluminal on Steam&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The puzzles are incredible.&lt;br&gt;
It has this game mechanic that tricks your mind. Even when you understand it, it still leaves you in awe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know me, you know where this is going&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
I wondered how would it feel to interact with this game mechanic in the real world.&lt;br&gt;
I am really into VR and that is probably the only environment (for now) that we could experience this game mechanic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also got me thinking&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
Is it even possible to do this in VR?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did some research and found this gold gem on youtube:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lFEIUcXCEvI&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;How do non-euclidean games work? | Bitwise&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video talks about what non-euclidian games are (super freaking cool is what they are).&lt;br&gt;
Fast forward to &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/lFEIUcXCEvI?t=646&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;10:46 in the video&lt;/a&gt;
 and it explains how the game mechanic in Superluminal works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gotta say&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;hellip; I was a &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bit Wiser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; after watching that video!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img  src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/memes/ba-dum-tss.png&#34;
        alt=&#34;ba dum tss&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-does-the-game-mechanic-work&#34;&gt;How does the game mechanic work?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video puts it really well &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;as you pick up an object, its perspective stays the same, but its real size changes dramatically.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Meaning, something small that you pick up on a table, becomes really big if you point it at some place far away.&lt;br&gt;
There are all sorts of interesting puzzles that you can make with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logic behind this mechanic is super simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you pick up the object, you store
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the current distance from the player to the object and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also the current scale value of the object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As you move the object in the world, push it as far as you can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With that object in that position,
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get that distance and initial distance stored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this gives you a ratio that you can use to calculate the scale that the object should have in this new distance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mind was blown. 🤯&lt;br&gt;
It makes so much sense AND it is so clever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-did-i-go-about-building-this-in-vr&#34;&gt;How did I go about building this in VR?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am familiar with making VR things in Unity, so that was an easy choice for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I decided to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first make the mechanic work in a regular 2D screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and then tackle how it work work in VR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure there would be more to it then the simple math.&lt;br&gt;
It turns out that the hardest part, to me, was figuring out where to place the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the ways I tried doing that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attempt-1-push-the-object-backwards-a-little-bit-every-frame&#34;&gt;Attempt #1: Push the object backwards a little bit every frame&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That initially worked well.&lt;br&gt;
However, but once my object was far away and I looked at something that was close, when my object was already passed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added a Raycast to check if whatever I was pointing at was closer to where the object currently was.&lt;br&gt;
That didn&amp;rsquo;t solve the problem entirely. The Raycast is a very thin line so the object I was holding would stay behind another object until I actually aimed into an object that was closer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I tried something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attempt-2-at-every-frame-calculate-farthest-position-starting-from-the-closest-position&#34;&gt;Attempt #2: At every frame, calculate farthest position starting from the closest position&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually worked out very well.&lt;br&gt;
There are probably other solutions that are more efficient.&lt;br&gt;
I actually spent a couple of hours over the weekend trying different ways, but I took a little break and remembered what my goal was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; to experience this in VR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not A Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; to make the most efficient mechanic in the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;calculating-the-farthest-the-object-can-be&#34;&gt;Calculating the farthest the object can be&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is actually an interesting problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we know we can place an object at a certain position?
Unity does not give us a way to do a collision check on demand given a collider (if it does, let me know!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to do that check, I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.unity3d.com/ScriptReference/Physics.CheckBox.html&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unity&amp;rsquo;s Physics Check Box collision&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
To define the box size, I used an approximation.
I scaled the box size to what the object&amp;rsquo;s scale would be at a certain point.&lt;br&gt;
It is not perfect, but it works with most shapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-else-could-we-do-this&#34;&gt;How else could we do this?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many other ways.&lt;br&gt;
I think one of the best solutions would be for each object to have a component that calculates how far it can be pushed back given an initial position and direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that way, simple objects can use something like I mentioned above. Complex objects can implement something that checks for collisions using different shapes and sizes. (for example, an object with holes in it, like a donut.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mathematician in me also likes the other possibility to figure out a set of boxes which can fill an object&amp;rsquo;s space.&lt;br&gt;
That could be using in some preprocessing function or in realtime.&lt;br&gt;
During the &amp;ldquo;push back operation&amp;rdquo;, we check if any of the boxes are collisind with anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this was a weekend project. So I brought myself to focus on the task.&lt;br&gt;
(As I write this, I have this itch to go back and give these other options a try&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;experiencing-it-in-vr&#34;&gt;Experiencing it in VR&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there are a few things to think about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we pick up an object?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which direction do we push it away?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-pick-up-the-object&#34;&gt;How to pick up the object?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two ways I thought about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick up the object by grabbing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a pointer (or some cool &amp;ldquo;perspective wand&amp;rdquo;) to point to select an object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grabing the object would be really cool, because it would give you the extra idea that &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t be placing this really far away, it is right here in my hands&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br&gt;
However, I would have to change how the mechanic work to actually just place the object far away, when I actually let go of the object, which meant changing my current implementation. So I decided to maybe try that later. (I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went with option two. Simple click pointer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;which-direction-do-we-push-it-away&#34;&gt;Which direction do we push it away?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want the object to scale in relation to the position of our eyes,
but we want to use our hands to place the object in different locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then, the direction to push the object becomes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;from: the middle point in between the player&amp;rsquo;s eyes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to: the location where the hand is pointing to (raycast from the hand&amp;rsquo;s/wand&amp;rsquo;s forward position to whatever we hit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is very similar to the 2D screen effect.&lt;br&gt;
Except that in that frame of view, we are always pointing at the center of the camera and the camera is always moving to where we are pointing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and that is it!&lt;br&gt;
It does work in VR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-did-it-feel-to-use-this-perspective-wand-in-vr&#34;&gt;How did it feel to use this &amp;ldquo;perspective wand&amp;rdquo; in VR?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels like doing magic!
I threw together a bunch of assets in a scene and went crazy with moving them around.&lt;br&gt;
I tricked myself many times.&lt;br&gt;
I sometimes still get tricked when I place something in the sky without realizing.&lt;br&gt;
When that happens, the object starts to fall very slowing and that is what makes me realize that the object is really far away and also veeery large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-can-i-try-it&#34;&gt;Where can I try it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hosting a WebGL (non-vr) version that you can give a try here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://unfolding-dragon.github.io/perspective-wand/&#34;&gt;https://unfolding-dragon.github.io/perspective-wand/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also built for a couple of other devices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/unfolding-dragon/perspective-wand/releases/tag/v0.1&#34;&gt;https://github.com/unfolding-dragon/perspective-wand/releases/tag/v0.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is my motto? this up here ^ </title>
      <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/motto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.tiago.dev/motto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was taking a class in called &amp;ldquo;How To Make Great Decisions&amp;rdquo; at the Seattle community college (thanks Microsoft for sponsoring it!),&lt;br&gt;
I had to keep a daily journal. One of the questions I had to answer in one of these days was &amp;ldquo;What is your motto?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I thought about it, my mind went straight to a message that I used to written on a mirror right outside my bedroom.&lt;br&gt;
The message was &amp;ldquo;The Staying Speed = The Right Effort + Time&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was something I came up with a long time ago when I used to practice kung fu. I used to read a lot about Jeet Kune Do and quotes/teachings from Bruce Lee and in those, I derived this motto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To me, the meaning behind &amp;ldquo;The Staying Speed&amp;rdquo; is&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;hellip;about finding the right amount of time and effort needed to reach a goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put too little effort and time (how often you do something) and you won&amp;rsquo;t accomplish it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put too much effort and time and you might get burned out, bored, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Staying Speed&amp;rdquo; is&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
the right balance of the amount of effort and time you put into a goal.&lt;br&gt;
The speed is not always the same. It depends not only on what you are working on, but your emotional state as well.
Knowing that, allows you to recognize when it is too little and when it is too much. From there you can adjust your staying speed to accomplish your goal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first table!</title>
      <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/projects/first-diy-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/projects/first-diy-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width:100%&#34; src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/woodwork/first-diy-table-07.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;my first table!&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-did-i-build-a-table&#34;&gt;Why did I build a table?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work desk was bending after about 1 year of working from home.&lt;br&gt;
My office equipment is actually pretty heavy.&lt;br&gt;
So I decided to build a table!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-not-just-buy-one&#34;&gt;Why not just buy one?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like building things.&lt;br&gt;
and some youtube videos claimed I could make one for under $100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and  the biggest reasons were that if I build one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;would be fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would learn a new skill!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-did-i-go-about-it&#34;&gt;How did I go about it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched tons and tons of youtube videos to learn the different techniques and styles for building a table.&lt;br&gt;
I mentioned to my buddy Matt that I wanted to build a table and he told me that he had ALL THE TOOLS! for building a table.&lt;br&gt;
He saved me a lof of money on renting/buying the tools 😁
(Thanks Matt!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan was to build something like a workbench.
Instead of having a full frame at the bottom, I wanted to space for my chair and legs.&lt;br&gt;
I also love tables that can easily move, so I knew I had to put some casters on it as well 😈&lt;br&gt;
(the casters definitely pushed the cost to over $100)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mistakes&#34;&gt;Mistakes!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a couple of rookie mistakes while building the table (as most people do when trying things for the first time).&lt;br&gt;
The biggest mistake was getting the wrong measurements, but I was able to turn those bugs into features of my desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bug-to-feature-1&#34;&gt;Bug to Feature #1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legs were a bit too short, so instead of having the legs go all the way up to the top frame, they are a bit lower, which gave me the right height and it gave a little space where I can hang my headset on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bug-to-feature-2&#34;&gt;Bug to Feature #2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got my plywood, I asked them to cut to the wrong size.&lt;br&gt;
I had the right measurements, but I had this &amp;ldquo;imposter syndrome&amp;rdquo; when I was buying the plywood and I told them the wrong measurement&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
but now! I have a little door at the top of my table which I can pass cables below or easily hook things to the power strip I added on the table 😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-here-is-my-first-diy-workbenchtable&#34;&gt;So here is my first DIY Workbench/Table&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Materials
&lt;img  src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/woodwork/first-diy-table-00.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;The Materials&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My First 2 by 4 frame!
&lt;img  src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/woodwork/first-diy-table-01.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;my first 2 by 4 frame!&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laying the legs and casters
&lt;img  src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/woodwork/first-diy-table-02.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Laying the legs and casters&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;legs, bottom frame casters all attached
&lt;img  src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/woodwork/first-diy-table-03.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;legs, bottom frame casters all attached&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting a feel for the table
&lt;img  src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/woodwork/first-diy-table-04.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Getting a feel for the table&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glueing the table top
&lt;img  src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/woodwork/first-diy-table-05.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Glueing the table top&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staining the top
&lt;img  src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/woodwork/first-diy-table-06.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Staining the top&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done! and with all my work equipment setup
&lt;img  src=&#34;https://notes.tiago.dev/imgs/woodwork/first-diy-table-07.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Done! and with all my work equipment setup&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;am-i-going-to-do-more&#34;&gt;Am I going to do more?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely!&lt;br&gt;
I have plans to build a table for a tv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my plan is to actually undo a table I put together a couple of years ago and make two tables out of it. Use one and sell the other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some good youtube channels that explain how to build stuff with simple tools and materials:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChKlSK39lLg8eZHIX0iVzLA&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;DIY Creators&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCD02RAib9K0kob8UMWwLMSA&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Pneumatic Addict&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t use only them as your resources. There are tons of other videos and blogs where you can learn bits and pieces about what you might want to create.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/thoughts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes.tiago.dev/post/thoughts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-am-i-starting-a-blog&#34;&gt;Why am I starting a blog?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am creating this blog as a sort of a personal growth record keeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The posts I am creating are usually around the areas of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;books I am reading or listening to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my endless quest of working on projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a public &amp;ldquo;fuck yeah list&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I read and listen to book, I take notes.
Doing that really helps to critically understand what I am reading and it helps to retain knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short words, this method goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write what you think you are going to be reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read a chapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write about what you have just read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;before you start reading the book again, read through your notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some videos on the method I described:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z-GtGH57J9I&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Big Think : How to remember everything you read | Shane Parrish&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9fvUYmJcqWg&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Big Think : Want to get more from books? Stop reading them cover to cover. | Shane Parrish&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been tracking all the projects that I have been working on.
There are over 20 of them. None are never trully done.&lt;br&gt;
There is always something else to thinker with. Something else to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are my creative outlet. It is probably one of the things I enjoy doing the most in life.
Some of them are pretty cool and worth sharing, I think :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fuck-yeah-list&#34;&gt;Fuck Yeah List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is right. A &amp;ldquo;Fuck Yeah List&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br&gt;
I learned this &amp;ldquo;concept&amp;rdquo; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.docjamesw.com/&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Doc James Whittaker&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
It is simple a list of accomplishments that I am proud of.&lt;br&gt;
Whenever I need a pick me up, I can come here and read &amp;ldquo;my fuck yeah list&amp;rdquo; and feel better about myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>